<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blockchains on The Chiwbaka</title>
    <link>/categories/blockchains/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blockchains on The Chiwbaka</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/blockchains/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Winternitz OTS keypairs</title>
      <link>/post/2018-08-30-winternitz-ots-keypairs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-08-30-winternitz-ots-keypairs/</guid>
      <description>WOTS is a way of generating a public/private keypair, and using it for signing messages. In other words, it&amp;rsquo;s a signature scheme. Importantly, it only depends on having a good hash function, which makes it &amp;lsquo;quantum resistant&amp;rsquo; because Shor&amp;rsquo;s algorithm can make cracking elliptic curves easier on quantum computers (????). XMSS uses a tweaked version called WOTS+, which improves some cryptographical aspects which I don&amp;rsquo;t quite understand. A lot of what I learnt came from this page at Cryptography Services.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bitcoin mining - how does it work?</title>
      <link>/post/2018-02-22-bitcoin-mining-how-does-it-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-02-22-bitcoin-mining-how-does-it-work/</guid>
      <description>Economics Behind Mining To understand how mining really works, let&amp;rsquo;s first understand the economics behind it.
The network of computers running the coin software (let&amp;rsquo;s say Bitcoin) wants history (of transactions) to be recorded in the form of blocks, and it rewards those who do so with 12.5 BTC.
Bitcoin wants history to be recorded in a new block every 10 minutes. Additionally, since anybody could record history in a new block, it has to make sure that those who invested the most (electricity, stake, capacity etc) have a better chance of recording a new block, because those who invested the most are probably more interested in seeing Bitcoin work properly, as opposed to those who are trying to spend their Bitcoin twice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Concept of State in Blockchains</title>
      <link>/post/concept-state-blockchains/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2017 21:21:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/concept-state-blockchains/</guid>
      <description>While working on the code that makes up an actual cryptocoin, I&amp;rsquo;d always come across a class or something that would refer to a &amp;lsquo;State&amp;rsquo;. And I never really knew what that was.
Was that the state of the coin&amp;rsquo;s network, on the latest block? The state of that node perhaps - but how could the node have a valid state when it&amp;rsquo;s still busy downloading the blockchain?
It wasn&amp;rsquo;t until I read Ethereum&amp;rsquo;s whitepaper that the concept of state was formalized: it&amp;rsquo;s the state of the coin as your node sees it, with the blockchain data it has on your computer.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>