<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Chiwbaka</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on The Chiwbaka</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Winternitz OTS keypairs</title>
      <link>/post/2018-08-30-winternitz-ots-keypairs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-08-30-winternitz-ots-keypairs/</guid>
      <description>WOTS is a way of generating a public/private keypair, and using it for signing messages. In other words, it&amp;rsquo;s a signature scheme. Importantly, it only depends on having a good hash function, which makes it &amp;lsquo;quantum resistant&amp;rsquo; because Shor&amp;rsquo;s algorithm can make cracking elliptic curves easier on quantum computers (????). XMSS uses a tweaked version called WOTS+, which improves some cryptographical aspects which I don&amp;rsquo;t quite understand. A lot of what I learnt came from this page at Cryptography Services.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bitcoin mining - how does it work?</title>
      <link>/post/2018-02-22-bitcoin-mining-how-does-it-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-02-22-bitcoin-mining-how-does-it-work/</guid>
      <description>Economics Behind Mining To understand how mining really works, let&amp;rsquo;s first understand the economics behind it.
The network of computers running the coin software (let&amp;rsquo;s say Bitcoin) wants history (of transactions) to be recorded in the form of blocks, and it rewards those who do so with 12.5 BTC.
Bitcoin wants history to be recorded in a new block every 10 minutes. Additionally, since anybody could record history in a new block, it has to make sure that those who invested the most (electricity, stake, capacity etc) have a better chance of recording a new block, because those who invested the most are probably more interested in seeing Bitcoin work properly, as opposed to those who are trying to spend their Bitcoin twice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Concept of State in Blockchains</title>
      <link>/post/concept-state-blockchains/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2017 21:21:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/concept-state-blockchains/</guid>
      <description>While working on the code that makes up an actual cryptocoin, I&amp;rsquo;d always come across a class or something that would refer to a &amp;lsquo;State&amp;rsquo;. And I never really knew what that was.
Was that the state of the coin&amp;rsquo;s network, on the latest block? The state of that node perhaps - but how could the node have a valid state when it&amp;rsquo;s still busy downloading the blockchain?
It wasn&amp;rsquo;t until I read Ethereum&amp;rsquo;s whitepaper that the concept of state was formalized: it&amp;rsquo;s the state of the coin as your node sees it, with the blockchain data it has on your computer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generating Jules Verne novels with Torch-RNN</title>
      <link>/post/generating-jules-verne-novels-torch-rnn/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 May 2017 11:03:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/generating-jules-verne-novels-torch-rnn/</guid>
      <description>Torch-RNN is a rewrite of Andrej Karpathy&amp;rsquo;s char-rnn. You train it on some text, and then it can generate &amp;lsquo;similar&amp;rsquo; text. I loved reading Jules Verne novels, so being able to just crank out some new novels whenever I feel like it sounds like a great idea right?
The hardest part was setting the environment up.
The text preprocessor was written in Python 2, and you&amp;rsquo;d think &amp;ldquo;hey it&amp;rsquo;s just wrangling some text what requirements does it need&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apple&#39;s custom GPU, Imagination</title>
      <link>/post/2017-04-06-apples-custom-gpu-imagination/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2017 17:02:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2017-04-06-apples-custom-gpu-imagination/</guid>
      <description>Apparently Imagination lost 60% of its stock value after it was revealed that Apple wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be shipping its PowerVR GPUs within two years.
60%. Do you know what that means? It means many people were surprised. But why? If people had kept their heads to the ground they&amp;rsquo;d have noticed long ago.
Apple was always about vertical integration. The custom CPUs were already a big sign. And back in October 2016, the incredible David Kanter already published an article about A Look Inside Apple&amp;rsquo;s custom GPU for the iPhone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wordpress on Low Memory Servers</title>
      <link>/post/wordpress-low-memory-servers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2017 14:57:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/wordpress-low-memory-servers/</guid>
      <description>This site runs on a 512MB DigitalOcean droplet. Every week or two the Linux kernel would kill MySQL for using too much RAM&amp;hellip; and restarting it got tiring.
When I first start nginx, php-fpm and MySQL, the memory usage starts at 370MB and only goes upwards from there. htop (and journalctl) tells me that MySQL is the biggest offender, so let&amp;rsquo;s start there.
MySQL After some googling one parameter always popped up in every guide: innodb_buffer_pool_size.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Python to Google Go and Life</title>
      <link>/post/python-google-go-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2017 09:38:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/python-google-go-life/</guid>
      <description>Now that I&amp;rsquo;m an adult, I find that doing things on the side these days is nigh unsustainable when one has to spend most of the day making a living. Besides working out almost everyday and reading articles on entrepreneurship like I used to devour articles on dating, there&amp;rsquo;s no time left but to get a good 8 hours of sleep.
But recently I got a chance to study Golang.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t add Django migrations to version control</title>
      <link>/post/dont-add-django-migrations-version-control/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2017 14:11:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/dont-add-django-migrations-version-control/</guid>
      <description>Django docs recommend a lot of things which don&amp;rsquo;t really work out in reality.
For instance, having a single settings.py file. The only reason I can think of having it this way is so as not to overwhelm newcomers, because you need different settings for dev, production and staging. A single tests.py for an app. Seriously, guys? You need test_views.py, test_models.py, test_manager.py, at least.
And here&amp;rsquo;s the one thing that might be useful, might not: committing your migrations to version control.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Easily Understandable Machine Learning Tutorials</title>
      <link>/post/machine-learning-tutorials/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2017 15:37:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/machine-learning-tutorials/</guid>
      <description>Machine Learning  Dr Jason Browniee&amp;rsquo;s Machine Learning Mastery is for everybody, even total beginners, who&amp;rsquo;ve heard the hype about ML, and want to get in on the action. It&amp;rsquo;s step by step, simple and very easy to follow.
 Once one has done quite a few chapters into Machine Learning Mastery it&amp;rsquo;s good to check out ujjwalkarn&amp;rsquo;s Github list of Machine Learning and Deep Learning Tutorials.
  Neural Networks  If you&amp;rsquo;re totally new to neural networks, Andrej Karpathy&amp;rsquo;s Hacker&amp;rsquo;s Guide to Neural Networks is hands down the best.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>